# C H I R A N J E E V

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT
CAPGEMINI

https://jainchiranjeev.dev

cjain 252@gmail.com



### **ABOUT ME**

Passionate Software Developer with experience in Core Java, native Android Development and C# .NET. Experienced in development and implementation of Client-Server applications in Java and Android. Various modules of android application development and several projects to back that up. Java and Android Development are my forte.



# **CONTACT**

Address:

Airoli, Navi Mumbai

Mobile:

+91 756 770 2491

Email:

cjain252@gmail.com

Skype: cjain252



## **SKILLS**

JAVA PROGRAMMING ANDROID APP DEVELOPMENT

 ${\sf MYSQL}, {\sf SQL} \ {\sf SERVER}$ 

C#.NET

HTML/CSS/JS

AMAZON AWS RDS, S3, BEANSTALK

WEB DEVELOPMENT

GIT

ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR & XD

AND MORE



## **EXPERIENCES**

#### ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT CAPGEMINI INDIA

OCT, 2017 - PRESENT

- Worked with a team for the creation of an in-house code coverage tool with Java, SpringBoot, MySQL and Angular.
- Built a Find and Reserve Utility for internal teams working on Data using SQL Server, SpringBoot & some basic Angular for front-end.
- Worked with various teams on and offshore for upgrading a major application built on .NET, SQL Server and hosted on IIS Server.

#### ANDROID DEVELOPER

#### **FREELANCER**

JUL, 2016 - PRESENT

- Involved in full lifecycle of the projects including design, development and deployment to build intuitive, robust and pixel-perfect applications while also working on back-end systems.
- Worked with various architecture components like Jetpack/AndroidX, ViewModel & LiveData, Services, BroadcastListeners, SOLite Databases and more.
- Worked on various tools for responsive functionalities like Google Cloud Messaging, Firebase Auth, Realtime Database, Analytics & Ads, Picasso, ButterKnife, Graphs and more.
- Experienced with AWS for hosting backend systems as well as databases on S3, Beanstalk and RDS.

All the projects use Git for version control and collaboration with other developers.



## **EDUCATION**

# LDRP-ITR, GANDHINAGAR BE (COMPUTER ENGINEERING)

2013 - 2017

I finished my Computer Engineering degree with a CGPA of 8.59. My subjects of interest were Java and Android development.

Mini Project: NFC Driven Door Locks

Final Year Project: Pedestrian Detection using OpenCV



## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Oracle Certified Associate Java Programmer (1Z0-808)

2016

Microsoft Certified C# Developer (70-486)

2018